Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/alihajian (LinkedIn) alihajian.com (Personal) github.com (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Data Science
Machine Learning
Research

Languages

Arabic (Elementary)
Persian (Native or Bilingual)
Malay (Elementary)
English (Native or Bilingual)

Honors-Awards

Best Programmer Award
6 Dean's List Academic Awards
Free Membership Award
Full Sponsorship Award
Best Undergraduate Publication

Publications

Feature Extraction from EEG Data for a P300 Based Brain-Computer Interface

Ali Hajian

Award-winning Machine Learning Engineer with demonstrated experience across different domains

Kuala Lumpur

Summary

I began working on machine learning projects in 2016 when I joined the University of Otago in New Zealand as a Research Assistant. I have worked on projects ranging from simple natural language and image processing to advanced feature extraction and classification of human brain EEG. Since 2017, I have been working as a Machine Learning Engineer at PETRONAS research centre. At this position, I develop AI solutions that assist geoscientists in exploration of oil and gas through analysis of complex geophysical data such as well log and seismic.

My research experience in applying data science across industries and disciplines have equipped me with substantial knowledge that would benefit any data science team. More importantly, these experiences are the tangible proofs of my flexibility and ability to apply my skills in new technical domains; domains that are often alien to a typical data scientist.

Experience

PETRONAS RESEARCH SDN. BHD. Machine Learning Engineer December 2017 - Present (4 years 1 month)

Malaysia

- Developing ML-based software solutions for exploration of oil and gas, especially Quantitative Interpretation and reservoir characterization.
- Achieved higher oil and gas classification accuracy than previously developed models.
- Co-founded PETRONAS Artificial Intelligence and Deep Learning Club.

University of Otago Research Assistant May 2016 - December 2016 (8 months)

New Zealand

Project Title: An Efficient Brain-computer Interface

- Investigated the influence of different learning models and feature extraction methods on a brain-computer interface.
- Improved system performance by almost 6%.
- Published an academic paper in Lecture Notes in Computer Science.

Universiti Teknologi PETRONAS Research Assistant September 2015 - December 2015 (4 months) Malaysia

Project Title: A Hybrid Intelligent System for Production and Quality Assurance of Composite Materials' Application in Drilling Pipes

Sahab Smart Domain Co-founder & ICT Manager March 2007 - December 2011 (4 years 10 months)

Sahab Smart Domain is a company specialized in marketing.

Education

Universiti Teknologi PETRONAS

Bachelor of Technology (Honours), Information and Communication Technology \cdot (2014 - 2017)

Universiti Teknologi PETRONAS

Foundation, Technology · (2012 - 2013)

Saba High School

Pre-University Diploma, Mathematical Science (2011 - 2012)